<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<!--
  16x Map Fix Companion - Texture Streaming Budget
  "The Man, The Mythos, The Legend : KeilerHirsch"   (GNU GPL v3 or later)

  Mod name = "FS25_16xMapFix" (final). It must stay identical on
  server and client for multiplayer, and must match COMPANION_MOD_NAME in the
  tool's configure_companion.py so the VRAM auto-config writes the settings file
  this mod reads.
-->
<modDesc descVersion="106">
    <author>KeilerHirsch</author>
    <version>1.0.0.0</version>
    <iconFilename>icon.dds</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>

    <title>
        <en><![CDATA[16x Map Fix Companion - Texture Budget]]></en>
        <de><![CDATA[16x Map Fix Companion - Texturspeicher]]></de>
    </title>

    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[Companion to the 16x Map Fix map tool.

Farming Simulator 25 caps high-resolution texture streaming at roughly 4 GB of graphics-card memory by default. On large (16x / 32x) maps that starves the terrain and causes texture flicker and pop-in. This mod raises the cap to a value you set ONCE in a plain settings file - no code editing - and it survives mod updates.

The value lives in:  modSettings/FS25_16xMapFix.xml  (created automatically on first run). Rule of thumb: set vramGiB to your graphics-card memory in GB minus 2.

Client-side rendering setting only: it changes no gameplay, no savegame and no multiplayer state, so it is fully multiplayer-safe.

Only use it if your graphics card has MORE than 4 GB of VRAM.

"The Man, The Mythos, The Legend : KeilerHirsch"]]></en>
        <de><![CDATA[Begleit-Mod zum 16x-Map-Fix-Kartentool.

Farming Simulator 25 begrenzt das Streaming hochaufloesender Texturen standardmaessig auf rund 4 GB Grafikkartenspeicher. Auf grossen (16x / 32x) Karten reicht das nicht und es kommt zu Textur-Flackern und Nachladen. Diese Mod hebt das Limit auf einen Wert an, den du EINMAL in einer einfachen Einstellungsdatei setzt - ohne Code zu bearbeiten - und der Mod-Updates uebersteht.

Der Wert steht in:  modSettings/FS25_16xMapFix.xml  (wird beim ersten Start automatisch angelegt). Faustregel: vramGiB = Grafikkartenspeicher in GB minus 2.

Reine clientseitige Render-Einstellung: aendert kein Gameplay, keinen Spielstand und keinen Multiplayer-Zustand - damit voll multiplayer-sicher.

Nur verwenden, wenn die Grafikkarte MEHR als 4 GB VRAM hat.

"The Man, The Mythos, The Legend : KeilerHirsch"]]></de>
    </description>

    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/textureBudget.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
</modDesc>
